虽然梅奔没能拿下美国大奖赛
Mercedes couldn't win the United States Grand Prix yet,
但他们的赛车某些方面仍成为了周末最大的讨论点
something about its car still managed to be the weekend's biggest talking points.
上一场土耳其的比赛画面显示
Footage from the previous race in Turkey showed
W12赛车的尾部在直道上行驶时下沉得相当厉害
the W12 rear end sinking rather dramatically as it traveled down the straight.
这引起了美国和世界各地的车迷很大的兴趣
It was the subject of a lot of interest in America and among fans watching around the world.
但几天后小维斯塔潘的胜利则终结了梅奔拥有最快赛车的猜测
But Max Verstappen's Victory, a couple of days later, ended Mercedes' mini run of having the fastest car,
并证明了梅奔在后悬挂上的改进并没有一些人所认为的那么神
and proved this rear suspension trick is not quite the magic bullet, some might have assumed.
但它却在土耳其大奖赛上表现如此出众
But it has proven to be a very useful tool,
所以本期视频将解释你所看到的到底是什么 以及它是如何工作的
so we're going to explain exactly what it is you're seeing and how it works.
不是发动机的提升 而是一款"精巧的系统"?
土耳其大奖赛赛后 对手红牛车队领队霍纳表示
After the Turkish Grand Prix rival team boss Christian Horner said
红牛的赛车直道上根本追不上梅奔
Red Bull can't get near Mercedes on straight line speed,
看到它的动力单元有如此明显的性能提升 感觉非常惊讶
and it was surprising to see an apparent performance step from its power unit.
这催生了关于梅奔的额外速度来自何处的各种理论
That triggered various theories about where the extra speed had come from.
在土耳其 汉密尔顿的赛车更换了全新的内燃机
In Turkey, Lewis Hamilton had a fresh internal combustion engine,
因为梅奔一直在他们的V6发动机上有所纠结
as Mercedes has been battle in engine issues with its V6.
因此一种理论是梅奔从全新动力单元中获得了显著更高的性能
So one theory was, Mercedes was getting significantly more performance from a new power unit,
之后其性能会稳步降低
before its output steadily degraded.
还有人猜测梅奔已经发现并解决了其动力单元内的一些潜在泄漏问题
There has also been speculation
Mercedes had identified and addressed some potential leaks within its power unit.
这些泄漏问题一直在拖赛车性能的后腿
There had been depleting its performance levels
并导致夏休期以来一直困扰制造商的可靠性问题
and causing the reliability issues that have dogged the manufacturer since the summer break.
但梅奔没时间去理会这些流言
But Mercedes has little time for such rumors.
当天空体育F1向马桶狼提出
When it was put to him by Sky Sports F1
"梅奔发动机问题是'与发动机深处的空气阀门有关'时"
that its engine problem was "something to do with air valves deep in the engine".
他回复道"你们不要见得风是得雨 问那问题都给我整笑了"
Wolff replied: "You are being fed with a lot of bulls**t. But the questions are interesting."
梅奔动力单元上的流言貌似是烟雾弹
The focus on the power unit appears to be a red herring,
甚至红牛方面的语调也在美国大奖赛开始发生转变
and even Red bull's tune changed at the United States Grand Prix.
霍纳将焦点转向了梅奔操控赛车后部提升直道性能并降低阻力的方法
Horner instead turned the spotlight
on how Mercedes has found a way to manipulate the performance of the rear of the car on the straights
and reduce its drag levels.
土耳其站的画面展示了梅奔赛车尾部在高速下的压缩程度
Footage of the Mercedes from Istanbul showed how much the rear was compressing at high speed.
而在美国站练习赛中 霍纳甚至暗示梅奔激活了能显著降低赛车后部高度的系统
And during practice in the US, Horner even refer to a system Mercedes is activating now,
and how it's been able to drop the rear ride height so significantly.
马桶狼听到这些猜疑后回复说你可真会编啊
Wolff referred to the speculation as great stories and great narrative,
但当他说在后悬挂上的某种改动在F1中并不是新玩意时
but he did hint a specific effort to maximize the car's aero-efficiency,
也的确暗示了车队在最大化赛车空动效能上作出的努力
when he said that trying to work the rear suspension in a certain way is not a new practice in Formula 1.
他之后又说梅奔已经找到在赛车调教方面靠近那个"甜蜜点"的方法
And he went on to argue that
Mercedes has been able to understand how to hit the sweet spot of the car in terms of its set up.
这一切的大背景是赛季开始时梅奔的赛车在直线速度上是有优势的
The backdrop to all of this is that Mercedes started the year with a straight line speed edge
而之后红牛却统治了法国站与奥地利站
before Red Bull looked superior in France and Austria.
在那之后 梅奔貌似又重新获得了直道速度优势
Since then, Mercedes seems to have re-established its advantage.
并在意大利站 俄罗斯站 土耳其站中成为总体上最快的车
And it had the fastest car overall, in Italy, Russia and Turkey.
竞争态势的明显转变
Part of that apparent shift in the competitive dynamic
部分原因是梅奔在7月英国大奖赛上引入了新的空动套件
has been Mercedes introducing a new aerodynamic packaged at the British Grand Prix in July.
其优化的悬挂系统似乎已经与升级相一致
Its optimized suspension system seems to have arrived in line with the upgrade.
马桶狼表示他们花了一些时间来最大限度地提高该套件的效率
Wolff suggested it had taken some time to maximize the efficiency of that package,
但最近的比赛已经证明梅奔已经找到了突破口
but that the most recent races have proven that Mercedes has found a breakthrough.
马桶狼说
Wolff said
"我很喜欢看到团队围绕
如何靠近调教甜蜜点时散发的智慧之光"
"很明显 我们在银石赛道引入了升级
之后每场比赛都让我们更能理解如何最大程度压榨赛车性能"
"先是索契站 然后土耳其站 还有美国站这里
事实证明这绝对是一条正确的道路"
那么梅奔是如何在直道上将赛车后部的高度降低的?
So where does Mercedes dropping the rear ride high on the straights fit into this?
幸运的是 我们很容易找到一位前F1技术总监做出的解释
Fortunately, we have easy access to a former F1 technical director to help us explain.
梅奔到底干了啥?
赛事技术专家加里·安德森已经研究了多方证据
The race's technical expert Gary Anderson has studied the evidence
并把正在发生的事情拼凑到了一起
and peace together what appears to be happening.
接下来这段是视频作者拉关注 可以快进到  4:20
But before we pass it on, we need to say, thank you for making it this far.
Your support makes it possible for us to make videos like this one.
Chances are that you're watching this and you're not subscribe to the channel.
If that's the case, and you don't want to miss out on any of our videos in the future,
you can hit the big red button and turn on notifications to change that.
That way, you'll always see our videos as soon as they're published
and never miss something that we hope you're going to really enjoy.
下面我们一起来看看加里·安德森对梅奔的分析
But let's get into Gary Anderson's analysis of what Mercedes is doing.
当F1赛车的后扩散器接近地面时
As the rear diffuser of an F1 car gets closer to the ground,
通过底板主要平坦部分下方的气流
the airflow passing under the main flat part of the floor
无法快速通过 无法正常供给扩散器
can't move fast enough through there to feed the diffuser properly.
导致尾部气流失速 赛车下压力降低 阻力降低
This means the air flow stalls and the car loses down force and therefore drag,
这在直道上是很有优势的
which is very handy on the straights.
优化这种效果还有一个额外的好处 即能够使用更多的尾翼
Optimizing this effect comes with the additional advantage of being able to run more rear wing,
赛车在弯道有更高的下压力 又能因尾部扩散器气流失速而兼顾直道速度
which means more grip through the corners, but still with the straight line speed you need,
because the diffuser stalls.
这是所有车队共同的设计目标
That makes it a common objective.
而这对梅奔来说特别重要的原因是他们与阿斯顿·马丁的赛车
The reason this is of particular valley to Mercedes is that along with Aston Martin,
都是围场里的低倾角底板赛车
it has one of the two low rake cars on the grid.
也就是说梅奔的赛车后部本来就已经很接近地面了
That means the rear of the car is already closer to the ground,
很容易达到我们之前提到的气流失速状态
and makes it easier to achieve the stall we're talking about.
梅奔在银石的升级与车队试图实现其后悬挂改进的目的有关
Mercedes' Silverstone upgrade is relevant to what the teams trying to achieve of its rear suspension trick,
因为升级使前部的底板运行更高效
because it made the front corners of the under floor work harder.
而梅赛德斯可以利用这一点来让扩散器提早达到失速的临界点
And Mercedes can make use of that to get to the critical point
of making the diffuser stall just that bit earlier.
而关键却在悬挂系统自身的机构
But the behavior of the suspense in itself is key.
简单来讲 F1赛车的后悬挂系统在两边都有一个弹簧
In simple terms, the rear suspension of a Formula 1 car has a spring for each corner,
并在中央还有第三个摇摆弹簧连接两侧
and then there's a central heave spring that links those two corners.
当赛车左转时 右侧后悬挂弹簧压缩
So when the car goes round the left hander, the right side rear suspension will be in compression,
左边的弹簧伸长
while the left side will extend.
赛车右转时 左侧压缩 右侧伸长
And for a right hander, the left sides in compression, and the rights extending.
而赛车在直道上加速时 两侧悬挂的弹簧都会压缩
And when the car is going down the straight, both of those suspension linkages are compressing,
又因为两侧弹簧都压缩了 那第三个弹簧也会跟着被压缩
and because they're going in the same direction, the third spring is compressing as well.
同时 下压力是与速度平方成正比的
What you need to know is that the down force produce, rises at the square of the speed,
也就是说速度变成两倍 下压力会变成四倍
meaning that if you double the speed, you quadruple the down force.
所以随车赛车提速 对后悬挂系统的压力也在提升
So as the car goes faster and faster, the load builds on the rear suspension assembly.
而由于驱动第三根弹簧连杆的几何形状 导致该连杆可以"过中"
And because of the geometry of the linkages driving the third spring, that linkage can go "over center".
在这种情况下 第三根弹簧压缩率降低 变为向两侧伸长
In these conditions, the third spring reduces in its rate of compression and in turn support,
从而带动直道上加速的赛车后部降低
so as it's holding the car up in the straights, this means the rear will drop down.
当直道结束 车手踩下刹车 车身后部提升 扩散器重新获得气流
When the driver hits the brakes, the rear of the car will rise, and the diffuser airflow will reattach,
制造赛车刹车与过弯所需的下压力
producing the down force required for breaking stability and corner balance.
加里·安德森举了现实中家用车后备箱盖气弹簧的例子
The metaphor Gary Anderson likes to use is the gas struts on the rear tailgate of your car.
打开后备箱的时候 先是表现为阻力 而随后气弹簧支撑起了后半程的提升
When you open it, there's initially resistance, but then the gas strut takes over and lifts it,
而关后备箱时 一开始要用力往下压 随后力道变轻 最后它自己就能关上
and when you close it, you're initially pushing against it before it goes light and closes easily.
因为气弹簧的几何形状让它也"过中"了
That's because the geometry of the gas strut goes "over center".
当它"过中"的时候 会降低伸缩阻力 让你能够关上后备箱
And when it does this, it offers much lower resistance and allows you to close the tailgate.
这在原理上和梅奔赛车的后悬挂是一样的
In principle, that's exactly the same as the Mercedes' rear suspension.
这玩意合法吗?
而优化这种悬挂效果的关键是让它能在不同赛道环境中的正确速度下起作用
The key to optimizing this suspension effect
is to make it happen at the right speeds for the track configuration.
对不同赛道来说 确定连杆的几何形状非常重要
It's critical for each circuit to identify the linkage geometry
知晓何时弹簧会过中 保证它只在需要的时候才会起作用
and when it would go over center, so it only happens when you need it to.
你最不想看到的情况就是扩散器在过高速弯时失速
The last thing you want is for the diffuser to be stalling through a high speed corner.
也因此 梅奔赛车的该系统在美国赛道效率可能会有所降低
So that potentially reduced the effectiveness of this system for Mercedes in America,
因为第一赛段的连续高速弯需要第三弹簧能正常起到支撑起车身的作用
given the high speed sweeps of the first sector
where you need the third spring to work is normal to support the car.
果然这样的悬挂系统出现后 大家都在争论它是否符合赛事规则
Unsurprisingly, one of the questions that has cropped up since it became such a big topic
is how it can be legal.
如果后悬挂系统会为赛车带来空气动力学上的优势
If the rear suspension is being used for aerodynamic benefit,
那么可能会因经常引用的禁止可动赛车车身部件条例而被判定非法
that could be illegal under the often referred to ban on movable aero-devices.
F1技术规则(2021) 条款3.8
影响赛车空气动力特性的任何特定部分:
a. 必须遵守与车身有关的规则
b. 必须牢固固定在赛车全部弹簧支撑部分上(牢固固定指没有任何自由度)
除了第3.6.8条所述的车手可调整的车身(指DRS系统)(除了仅与之相关的最小部件)和第11.4 11.5和11.6条所述的部件外
赛车的任何影响其空气动力特性的特定部件必须与赛车弹簧支撑部分保持不动关系
在任何情况下 禁止任何设计用来弥合赛车弹簧支撑部分与地面之间的间隙的装置或结构
但在本例中却并不符合
But in this case, it isn't.
条款3.8里对这一规则的定义是禁止车身部件做相对于赛车的移动
Article 3.8 of the technical regulations defines this rule
in terms of prohibiting body work moving in relation to the car.
2005年雷诺质量避震器被禁用
虽然过去的确有机械装置因其自身空气动力效应而被判非法的案例
While there are cases in the past of mechanical devices
being declared illegal because of their aerodynamic effects,
但本例则完全是来自悬挂系统本身的特性
this is all about the characteristics of the suspension system.
正如在2020年初红牛认为梅奔DAS装置非法的案例中那样
As was established in the case
that declared the Mercedes DAS device illegal when it was challenged by Red Bull at the start of 2020,
重点是梅奔所做的一切都是在悬挂系统内
what matters is that everything Mercedes is doing is within the suspension system.
具有这种几何形状与第三根弹簧所带来的特性没有任何违法之处
There's nothing illegal about having characteristics of
both the geometry and the third spring that has this effect,
即使它能让车身发生移动
even though it moves the car.
第三根弹簧作为悬挂系统存在的意义并不是空气动力学上的
As the primary purpose of the suspension system, and the third spring is not aerodynamic,
所以毫无疑问 它是合法的
there's no question that it's legal.
而红牛随后也认可了这一点
And Red Bull has subsequently admitted that.
这完全是悬挂系统的几何形状与特性造就的机械系统
This is a mechanical system that is entirely the consequence of
the geometry and characteristics of the suspension,
本身也不需要任何液压装置或电子驱动
and doesn't require any hydraulic or electronic actuation.
F1赛车车身本来也会因为下压力的增加而降低 我们看到的就是这样的结果而已
And F1 car will move downwards under increasing load, and this movement is simply a result of that,
如果有独立的系统主动创造这样的效应才是非法
what would be illegal is if there is an independent system creating that Effect.
大家或许还会奇怪为什么红牛不把这套合法且高效的系统照搬过来
You might be wondering why Red Bull isn't just copying the system as it's observed,
given its legal and theoretically so effective.
可红牛的赛车是高倾角底板
But Red Bull runs high rake,
因此要让红牛赛车足够接近地面 使扩散器失速到同样的程度
so for it to get its car close enough to the ground to make the diffuser stall to the same extent
需要彻底重做赛车的空气动力学特性
would require a complete change in aerodynamic philosophy.
本赛季都跑到这了 肯定不现实
At this stage of the season, that isn't going to happen.
希望本期视频能让大家了解梅奔精巧的悬挂系统
We hope this video has been as useful for you to understand Mercedes clever suspension
as it was when we first had it explain to us.
感谢观看~
So leave us with the thumbs up if you enjoyed the video
and if you'd like more technical insight from Gary Anderson in the future,
just let us know in the comments and leave some suggestions on what you'd like him and us to dig into.